fish4.co.uk 2009-06-14

# fish4

* **This Privacy Policy**

fish4 trading limited, together with its fish4 Affiliates (defined at Clause 9 below) (" **fish4** "), is committed to protecting your personal information and other data provided to us via this and any other fish4 web site (" **Web Site** "). Please read this Privacy Policy carefully as it contains important information about the use of information that you provide to us. This Privacy Policy explains what information fish4 collects about you, and how we collect and use your information, including setting out the circumstances where we could provide it to third parties. You should also read the separate User Terms applicable to this Web Site. 

* **What information do we collect and what do we do with it?**

**2.1** To take advantage of some of our services (such as setting up a Personal Folder on the Web Site) you will be required to log on or register with the Web Site. We may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web Site. The information will be collected when you register with the Web Site in order to use any of the services available via the Web Site. 

**2.2** If you choose to advertise on the Web Site or request us to place your advert with a newspaper or magazine, certain personal information or data (including credit card and billing information) about you will be captured electronically or otherwise. In the event that such personal information or data is part of your advert, such personal information or data will be posted to the Web Site, newspapers and magazines, as applicable, and may by accessed by users of the Web Site and/or readers of the relevant newspapers and magazines. 

**2.3** We will use the information that we collect to personalise your experience on the Web Site, to help you log on in future and to continue to use the Web Site, and to help us select services or materials for inclusion on the Web Site that may be of interest to you. We may need to pass your information to third parties who help us to maintain, administer or develop the Web Site but, if so, that information is only given to those third parties for that limited purpose. 

**2.4** We also monitor traffic patterns and usage of our Web Site to help us improve our Web Site design and layout. We may pass this information to our partners or other third parties but it will not contain any personally identifying information. 

**2.5** fish4 may want to contact you to notify you of news about fish4, changes to the Web Site, special events or new services or products that we think may interest you or fish4 may use your details and information to communicate to you offers for services or goods from other companies within the fish4 group or other companies which we think may be of interest to you. However, fish4 will not contact you for these purposes unless you authorise us to do so by either ticking the relevant boxes (i.e. during registration on the Web Site) to authorise fish4 to make such contact or you provide such authorisation in writing to fish4 or electronically via the Web Site (if applicable). If, at any time thereafter, you change your mind and would rather not be contacted by fish4 (or the third parties described above) to receive such information, please send an email to [privacy@fish4.co.uk](mailto:privacy@fish4.co.uk) with an explanation that you no longer wish to receive such information or in the event that you have received a communication containing such information, please click on the "deactivate" link set out in that communication. In those circumstances, fish4 will not contact you again in relation to the information described above in this paragraph 2.5. However, fish4 and/or its group companies will still use your details to send you information and communications in relation to the services or products for which you have registered. 

**2.6** If you want to update any of your information held by fish4, you can either make certain changes on-line (by clicking on "change details" while you are logged in) or you can send an email detailing the required amendments to [privacy@fish4.co.uk](mailto:privacy@fish4.co.uk). 

**2.7** fish4 reserves the right to access and disclose personal data or information to comply with applicable laws and lawful government requests, to operate its systems properly, or to protect itself or its users. 

* **Sharing of Information with Third Parties**

**3.1** From time to time, fish4 may choose to pass your details to carefully selected, trusted third parties so that they can also provide you with details of other services or products that might be of interest to you. If you do not wish us to do so, you should follow the procedure set out in paragraph 2.5 above and we will not provide your information to third parties for such purposes. 

**3.2** We follow security procedures as required by the UK Data Protection Act 1998, in the storage and disclosure of personal information that you have given us, to prevent unauthorised access to such information. At times we may let you know about the products or services provided by carefully selected third parties. We will only deal with partners who comply with the UK Data Protection Act 1998 as amended from time to time) and any other applicable data protection legislation or regulations, or with whom we are satisfied have appropriate measures to protect data. However, fish4 shall have no liability to you in respect of any breach of security by a third party. 

* **Your Consent**

**4.1** You acknowledge and agree that: 

**4.1.1** in the course of using this Web Site or registering with it and any services offered via this Web Site, certain information about you will be captured electronically or otherwise and transmitted to fish4 or and, potentially, to any third parties as set out above or to third parties who host our web servers or assist us in maintaining this Web Site; and 

**4.1.2** fish4 may send your information outside of the European Economic Area for processing or use in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

**4.2** You consent to the use, storage, or processing of your personal information by fish4 (or any third party fish4 uses for carrying out credit checks) for the purposes of carrying out any credit checks in the event that you enter into any financial transaction with fish4. 

**4.3** If ordered by a court of competent jurisdiction to provide any of your personal information collected by fish4 as described in this Privacy Policy, you consent to fish4 providing such personal information to that court in accordance with the court's instructions. 

**4.4** By using this Web Site, you expressly agree to the collection and use of your information as set out above for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. 

* **Data Protection Indemnity**

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998, you acknowledge that in the course of you advertising goods or services on our Web Site, certain personal data about your employees, agents or subcontractors or certain personal data of third parties appearing in the advertising you requested to appear on our Web Site may be captured electronically or otherwise by us. If this is the case, you shall ensure that you have obtained the express consent of any employees, agents, subcontractors or any applicable third parties to the transfer of their personal data to us to use, store and process such personal information for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy, including where such personal data forms part of the advertising and is posted to the Web Site for accessed by users inside and outside of the European Economic Area. You shall indemnify fish4 from and against all claims by any employees, agents, subcontractors or any third parties arising out of your failure to obtain the consent described in this paragraph 5. 

* **Our Responsibilities - How does fish4 protect user information?**

**6.1** When you enter into on-line credit or other payment card transactions (e.g. ordering advertising services on the Web Site), we offer the use of a secure server. The secure server software encrypts the information that you input before it is transmitted to us. To prevent unauthorised access, we follow legally required security procedures in the storage and disclosure of information that you have given to us. This means that sometimes we may ask for proof of identity before we disclose personal information to you. 

**6.2** Areas of the Web Site where transactions are entered into, reviewed or transmitted may be password protected. You can help to preserve your privacy by never sharing your password with anyone else. 

**6.3** We seek to limit our employees' access to your information about you to those employees who need to have such information to service your account. We emphasise to our employees the confidential nature of user information and the high level of importance that fish4 places on maintaining this confidentiality. 

* **What are 'Cookies' and how do we use them?**

**7.1** **Cookies - What is a Cookie:** A cookie is a piece of information that a web site transfers to the cookie file of the browser on your computer's hard drive On visiting the Web Site, a cookie will be placed on your computer automatically by fish4's Web Site. fish4 may use two types of cookies from time to time: "persistent" cookies and "session" cookies. Session cookies are temporary cookies that remain in the cookie file of your browser until you leave the Web Site and persistent cookies are cookies which remain in the cookie file of your browser for much longer (though how long will depend on the lifetime of the specific cookie). More information regarding the use of cookies can be found at <http://www.aboutcookies.org/page-3>

**7.2** **fish4's Use of Cookies:** fish4 does not use its persistent or session cookies to store personal information about you. fish4 uses its cookies for monitoring load balancing between its servers while you are linked to the Web Site, to conduct analyses of user traffic, and to perform web log audits. Third parties advertisers may serve cookies via this Web Site but these are only used to serve advertisements from the Web Site's advert servers and to track whether these advertisements are clicked on by visitors to the Web Site. fish4 may pass the non-personal information collected by its cookies to third parties but only for the purposes of carrying out such monitoring, analysis or web log auditing, or for the purposes of tracking the number or anonymous users of the Web Site. 

**7.3** **How to reject/deactivate Cookies:** Most browsers accept cookies automatically but you have the ability to accept/decline cookies by altering the settings in your browser to prevent automatic acceptance of cookies. If you decline/disable cookies, you may not be able to use all the interactive features of the Web Site or the Web Site may not be available to you. To remove cookies from your web browser or to obtain further details on cookies, including information on persistent and session cookies, please go to <http://www.aboutcookies.org/page-3>

**7.4** **Information collected by fish4 via the Cookies:** If you do not want fish4 to continue to store the information described in paragraph 7.2 that it collects via its cookies, please tick this box . However, as fish4 needs to use such information to operate the Web Site, if you tick this box, you are not authorised to use the Web Site. If you tick this box and continue to use the Web Site, then such continued use will mean that you have given your consent to fish4 using the information collected via its cookies for the purposes described in paragraph 7.2 above. Please remember that fish4 does not use its cookies to collect or store personal information about you. 

* **Changes to Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to add to or change the terms of this Privacy Policy in our sole discretion, without prior notice to you. If we change this Privacy Policy, we will post the new Privacy Policy on the Web Site, and it will become effective from the time of posting to the Web Site. Please visit this Privacy Policy on a regular basis to make sure you have read the latest version and you understand what we do with your information. Wherever possible, we will give you notice of any changes prior to their implementation. 

* **General**

In this privacy policy, "fish4 Affiliates" shall mean any subsidiary or holding company of fish4, or any subsidiary of fish4 Ltd, the holding company of fish4, all as defined by Section 736 of the Companies Act 1985, as amended by the Companies Act 1989, and shall include: fish4jobs limited (Company Number 03961754); fish4cars limited (Company Number 03955815); and fish4homes limited (Company Number: 03943230). "fish4 Affiliate" shall mean one of the fish4 Affiliates, as applicable. 

* **Feedback**

If you have any queries or problems with regard to this Privacy Policy or the uses to which we put your information, please e-mail us at [privacy@fish4.co.uk](mailto:privacy@fish4.co.uk).
